Let's do things differently this time.
Like, so differently.
His name is Miles Morales.
He was bitten by a radioactive spider.
And he's not the only one.
He hasn't always had it easy.
And now he's on his own.
And he's not the only one.
You think you know the rest.
You don't.
I thought I knew the rest, but I didn't.
I didn't wanna hurt him.
But I did.
And he's not the only one.
Hey!
Yo, Def Leppard!
Gwen!
Is the song over?
- Seems over.\N-  Are you okay?
You don't hang out,\Nand you don't wanna talk.
I didn't join a band
- so I could talk about feelings.\N- I did.
I joined it\Nso I could hit my feelings with sticks.
Yo, if you don't tell someone\Nwhat's going on,
- you're gonna snap.\N- I'm fine.
That's not how someone\Nwho's fine would say that.
They'd say,\N"Great. Thanks. How are you?"
- I'm great. Thanks.\N- Whoa!
How are you?
Fine?
Gwen. Come on.
- I don't get you, man.\N- You're right!
I play drums.
I always wanted to be in a band.
Guess I just never found the right one.
In this line of work,
you always wind up a solo act.
Before Miles...
- How many did you take?\N- ...there was Peter.
- I think you look great. I don't know.\N- Is this that dangerous menace?
No, no, no. She seems like a good guy.
Why wear a mask\Nif you've got nothing to hide?
All right,\Nno politics at the dinner table.
Thank you, May.
But they didn't really know me.
- And I didn't really know him either.
- Touch him again, Ned.\N-  Gwen, it's okay.
Until it was too late.
-  Hey, Gwen.\N- Hey.
Peter?
What? No.
No, no, no.
What did you do?
I just wanted to be special.
Like you...
Gwen.
-  Gwen?\N- Don't worry.
Who's Gwen?
Everything's gonna be okay.
Don't.
- Everything's gonna...\N- Don't go.
Oh, Peter.
Peter?
I never really made another friend\Nafter that.
Except one.
But he's not here.
And there's no way to get there.
Pressure mounts
as Captain George Stacy\Nleads the manhunt for Spider-Woman.
Who is she?\NAnd why won't she show her face?
Peter Parker, an innocent young man...
I've known May and Ben Parker\Nfor 12 years.
Peter Parker ate at my table.
He was my daughter's best friend.
And I will not rest
until I find this Spider-Woman.
Hey, hey, hey. How's the band?
Uh... Uh, yeah, great.\NI quit so, you know...
- You did, huh? Okay.\N- ...thumbs up.
We, uh-- We caught a break\Nin the Spider-Woman case.
Oh.
That's good.
We're close.\NI'm telling you, I can feel it.
Me too.
It'll be good for us.
Don't be so sure.
She killed your friend.
- You don't know that.\N- What do you mean? I do know that.
- I was there. She ran from the scene.\N- Maybe she didn't have a choice.
- I got a job to do, Gwen.\N- It won't bring him back.
Uh, I don't wanna argue about this, okay?
Yeah, I can tell.
Say, uh...
too punk rock to give your old man a hug?
All units, possible superhuman event.
Guggenheim Museum.
- Oh. Hey, this could be it.\N- Suspect is Adrian Toomes.
- Also known as the Vulture.\N- So I'll see you later?
We don't know the full scale\Nof the threat yet.
Cool.
Uh, I'll call. I love you.
49-20, on scene.
We're gonna need\Nall the help we can get.
It's a real mess down here.
This is Captain Stacy. I'm five out.
I need you to look alive.\NGood chance our girl shows up.
Yuri, explain to me how a guy\Nwith a 40-foot wingspan
just waltzed\Ninto the Guggenheim unnoticed?
Hey, it's New York.\NEveryone's got their thing.
- Do we know what he wants?\N- Do you speak Italian?
- Uh, I'm an Irish cop.\N- Maybe you love pasta or something.
Everybody on my signal!
- Look out for signs of Spider-Woman!
Hey!
Yup, we got our sign.
How's the manhunt for me going?
-  You're under arrest!\N- Good to know!
Vulture!
- Screaming their name usually works.
I guess that worked.
I am the Vulture,\Nthe pinnacle of man's genius.
You're not my Vulture.\NWhat are you, made of parchment?
- What cursed world have you brought me to?
You're glitching, huh? Been there.
- Uh, where you from, bud?\N- I am an artist, an engineer.
Oh, great. A Renaissance man.
Ooh, let me guess.
You were having an espresso
in some old-timey\NLeonardo da Vinci dimension,
and suddenly a portal opens up\Nand you wind up here.
- Am I warm?\N- Yes, that's pretty much it.
Sidebar,
uh, maybe you could stop making a mess\Nof the art museum for no reason?
- You call this art?\N- We're talking about it, aren't we?
I mean, it's more of\Na meta commentary on what we call art,
but it's also art.
Oh, look. It's your cousin.
I wouldn't play with fire, dude.\NYou're kind of made of paper.
- Oh, no.
I'm sorry.\NWho exactly are you supposed to be?
It's classified.
- You're the Blue Panther.\N- No.
- The Caped Blusader?\N- No.
- Dark Garfield.\N- Stop.
Macho Libre.
I'm from another dimension.
You are?
Wow! Actually, I'm not confused.
- My name is Miguel O'Hara.
I lead an elite strike force dedicated\Nto the security of the multiverse--
- Actually, forget it.
Can you go to any dimension you want\Nwith that watch thing?
- It's much cooler than a watch.\N- Okay. Sensitive.
There is a big flying turkey\Nfrom the Renaissance
I have to bring to justice,\Nso if you don't mind...
It's all right, kid.
I'll take it from here.
Okay, knock yourself out.
Why are you saying it like that?
-  You're not funny!\N-  Eh, I don't know.
Been really fun cleaning up\Nyour shocking mess, by the way.
What mess?
-  Kingpin's collider.\N- What are you guys talking about?
- You shut up.\N- None of your business. Nosy.
We saved the multiverse.
You left a hole wide enough\Nfor guys like him
to randomly get shot\Ninto the wrong dimension.
Now I'm stuck putting everybody\Nback where they belong
before all of time and space collapses.
And don't even get me started\Non Doctor Strange
and the little nerd back on Earth-199999.
Who's Doctor Strange?
Sounds like he maybe\Nshouldn't practise medicine.
- Sorry, captain, can't talk right now.\N- Hey! Hey!
So you want me to handle this one or...?
Okay.
He's got hammerspace!
LYLA, can you please, you know...?
- Nah, you gotta say it first.
- Call for backup.\N- What?
- Call backup.\N- Come on.
- Please just call for--\N- I already called her.
But I enjoyed that.
Spider-Woman.
Me too.
Are you, uh...?
Oh, this?
We don't know the sex yet.\NMy husband wants it to be a surprise.
He's really corny. But so hot.
Will you adopt me?
- What?\N- What? What?
Guys, can we focus
on the big, fire-breathing threat\Nto time and space, please?
- Yep, yep, yep.\N-  Right.
- What about her?\N- No.
- We could use the help.\N- No.
- 'Cause she called you Dark Garfield?\N- No.
- Do you say anything but no?\N- No. Yes.
- Why not?\N- You know why.
Enough of this.
Take a good look at my Greek fire\Nfrom my backpack.
Don't let him out!
He'll disrupt the canon.
-  Go to the ground.\N- Will you get out of here?
We have you surrounded.
-  But I'm a good guy.\N-  You don't look like a good guy.
You're just gonna have to shut up\Nand trust me. No!
Mayday! Mayday! We're hit!
We're headed for the ground!
Clear the building!
Yeah, I think it's a Banksy.
That's what I was gonna do.
- Hands in the air!
Captain, come on.
- Suspect is armed.\N- With what? I'm out of webs.
Get down on the ground.
Which is it? Hands in the air\Nor get down on the ground?
- You're under arrest.\N- I just saved a bunch of people!
- For the murder of Peter Parker.\N- Come on.
- You have the right to remain silent.\N- You don't understand!
You don't understand.
Dad.
I've thought about telling you.
But you can see why I didn't want to.\NYou can see why I didn't wanna tell you.
I didn't murder Peter.
I didn't know it was him.\NI didn't have a choice.
How long have you been lying to me?
Can you just not be a cop for a second\Nand be my dad here and listen to me?
Do you really think I'm a murderer?
You're in this to help people, right?
Right?
Well, so am I.
And the way to help right now\Nis to listen to me.
Please, Dad.
You're all I have left.
- You have the right to remain silent.\N- What?
Anything you say can and will...
Dad, are you really this afraid of me?
- You have the right to an attorney.\N- Dad, stop!
Don't get any closer.
Hey! What--?
- Dad!\N- Hey, hey, hey. Come on.
Just breathe.
We got you. Right, Miguel?
LYLA, scan this mess.
No further anomalies.
Canon remains intact.
We can't just leave her here.
She's doing this on her own.
I don't know how to fix this.
Yeah.
Well, join the club.
I know he's just a sophomore,
but we wanna get a jump\Non the college conversation, so...
I'm sure he's gonna be here any minute.
He's very serious about his future.
Uh...
- Excuse me, do you have an ATM machine?\N- Around there in the back.
Preferably not chained.
-  What?\N-  Nothing!
This should be simple enough.
Just make a hole...
grab the money.
Nope. That's not right.
Just get...
Uh--
Give me your money.
Where are you, money? Where are you?
Come here!
Oh!
Hey, who left this ATM on the sidewalk?
- Yo, what you doing back there, man?\N- Nothing.
Nothing.\NEverything's cool, man. It's all good.
- Just forgot my PIN number.\N- Get out of here!
- No! Sir! Let me rob you!\N- I'm going to rob your spotted face.
No reason to bring wood into this.
I've never robbed anybody in my life.\NPlease don't make this a bad experience.
"Bad experience"? I run a business here.
I'm like Robin Hood,\Nif he gave to himself.
Oh, wow, is this curry powder?\NSee, I'm a scientist. Or I wa-- I am.
Anyway, you've heard of Alchemax?\NI used to work there.
I was considered handsome\Nby scientists' standards.
I had a little accident.
Give me my foot!
Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
First of all, I'm not even robbing you.\NThis machine doesn't even belong to you.
- Belongs to the bank, the real criminals.\N- You're the criminal. You're robbing me.
You know, I can't really get a job\Nanywhere anymore, being like this.
So I've turned to a life of crime.
- Why do people say "ATM machine"?\N-  Huh?
- Who said that?\N- The M stands for "Machine."
Spider-Man!
Ow!
Hey, Lenny, how much do I owe you\Nfor this beef patty, man?
Spidey, if you catch him,\Nit's on the house, brother.
- This is real!\N- So are you, like, a cow or a Dalmatian?
I am...
...the Spot.
- We meet again, Spider-Man.
- That's funny to you?\N- Of course not. No.
So is that a costume?
Unfortunately for both of us,\Nthis is skin.
Oh, dang.
You see...
- I'm from your past. One year ago--
- Hold up.
- Oh, come on.\N-  Uh-oh.
- This has been fun.\N- Who you talking to?
- But I really gotta wrap this up.\N- Are you gonna be a while? 'Cause--
Maybe just pay me now.
Okay, let's do this one last time.
- My name is Miles Morales.
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
And for the last year and four months,
I've been\NBrooklyn's one and only Spider-Man.
And things are going great.
- Hey, hey, hey!
You could hurt somebody.
Catching all sorts of bad guys.
Let's go.
Oh!
Can't you act like a regular supervillain\Nso I can catch you?
I designed my new suit\Nwith some fly ambience down the side.
Aunt May moved to Florida.
Done.
I guest-hosted Jeopardy!
Endorsed baby powder.\NApologised for endorsing baby powder.
I made a mistake.
My moustache came in.
Moustache.
And out.
I made another mistake.
Been developing a new twist\Non my venom thing.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Sorry!
How much longer\Ncan I keep lying about who I really am?
I hear that new Spider-Man\Nis Puerto Rican.
Nah, he seems more Dominican to me.
I mean, would they get it if I told them?
We love you and accept you, even though\Nyou have been lying to us for a year.
Maybe in some other universe.
Sometimes I just wish\NI wasn't the only one.
But I don't dwell on it.
I miss my uncle sometimes.
Miles, I see exactly\Nwhat you're doing there, man.
Even though he turned out\Nto be the Prowler.
I try to do what he told me:
Just keep going.
"Just keep going."
You're looking at texts?\NThis is the fight of our lives.
- Sorry. Just a second.\N- Okay.
No, no, no. Go ahead. Take the call.
You turn off your phone in a theatre,\Nbut not when you're fighting me?
Ah! "In a minute."
Ah! He wrote it all as one word.\NThat's cute, right? The youth.
-  Okay, that's weird.\N- Whoa!
Oh, my nose!
Sorry. I gotta be somewhere.
- Psych.\N- Whoa!
There's bubbles now. Hold on.
Whoa!
I think this is going great.
Still bubbles on here.
I think it's probably okay.
I love it.
We're figuring it out.\NWe're finding our rhythm.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey, where'd that goose come from? Whoa!
I don't think I want this costume anymore.
Almost there, Mami.
- Smiley-face. Prayer hands.\N-  Oh, my God.
Is this your goo--?\NGet it off me, get it off me!
At the end of the day...
I got you right where I-- Ow!
So aggressive!
...I'm Spider-Man.\NNo one can take that away from me.
Unbelievable. Come back to your nemesis!
Don't escape.
Your costume's too tight in the back,\Nby the way.
- Yo, what's up, man?\N- Uh, I'm writing an essay.
There's a bad guy\Non the Petersen building.
Call the police, tell them to pick him up?
- Sounds like a slippery slope.\N- Just this one time.
It starts with one call,
then it's walkie-talkies,\Nsynchronised watches.
In a month, it'll be a Spider-Signal.\NI'm not your "guy in the chair."
Are those my Jordans?
I can't help it if we're the same size.
You see, every person is a universe.
And my job is to capture\Nyour person's universe
on this piece of paper.
- That's blank.\N- Exactly.
I have no idea who this kid is.
I don't know if he knows.
He's gotta decide if he's going\Nto commit himself to his future
or whatever he's doing\Ninstead of being here.
Can't have your cake and eat it too.
Unless you bake two cakes.
- Miles?\N- Interest in comedy.
- How's this going? College!\N- Now, son, what do we always say?
"On time means five minutes early."
I know, I know, I know.
I gotta get back to being a great student,\Nso can we make this quick?
Okay.
Miles's grades are pretty good.
A in AP Physics...
That's my little man.
...and AP Studio Art.
He takes after his uncle.
- A-minus in English.\N- She's a tough grader.
And a B in Spanish.
- What?!\N- Whoo! Okay.
- Miles!\N- Are you trying to kill your mother?
Eso no es my fault.
"Esto no es my fault"?\N¿Tú estás tomando la clase en Spanglish?
I missed a few classes.
Oh, just a few classes.\NWell, what's "a few"?
I mean, you know, like...
- Five?\N-  Five?!
Actually, six.
- You're dead.\N- A truant.
- Wait.\N-  Takes after his uncle.
- But I just have a lot going on.\N- All right. We can still salvage this.
I'm sorry, "salvage"?
Miles has a great story to tell.
Having a story at all seems gross.
- Your name is Miles Morales.\N- Correct.
You grew up\Nin a struggling immigrant family.
I'm from Puerto Rico.\NPuerto Rico is part of America.
We own a floor in Brooklyn.\NAh... Struggling?
- Doesn't matter. You're all struggling.\N- I make captain next week.
Now his dream is to attend\Nthe top physics programme in the nation...
- Whatever it takes, we'll do it.\N- ...at Princeton University.
In New Jersey?
No, no, no. That's too far.
New Jersey's too far from New York?
There's great schools in Brooklyn.
Mom, Princeton has the best\Nquantum researchers in the country.
Quantum. Mm-hm.
They're moving electrons\Nacross dimensional thresholds.
- Electrons. Uh-huh.\N- They're studying dark matter!
I don't know what any of that means.
I could help figure out\Nhow to travel to other dimensions.
- Yeah, okay.\N- That sounds like a really good fake job.
Dad, when you were my age,\Nyou followed your dream
and went out on your own\Nto start a business with Uncle Aaron.
- Right?\N- That's different. We used to--
See, when you were born--\NPlus, your mom used to--
Look, life is a journey.
You all got me into this school because\Nyou thought I could do something special.
- And now I think so too.
And the special thing I wanna do is this.
There are people out there
who can literally teach me\Nthe things I wanna learn.
But they aren't all in Brooklyn.
That's your story!
Now just stick to the script.
Miles, are you paying attention?
- Miles, pay attention.
- Ow. That hurt my tailbone.\N-  Are you kidding me?
Ooh. I gotta go. You guys keep talking.\NThis is all great stuff.
Miles, wait.\NDid you order the cake for tonight?
Totally. I'm-- You know, call me--\NI gotta go, all right? Bye!
This kid. I swear,\Nwhat are we gonna do with him?
All units, supervillain event in progress.
- I gotta go too.\N- What? You're gonna leave too?
He leaves, you leave, everybody leaves.\NWhy am I here?
I know. I'm so sorry.\NBut we'll figure it out.
Together.
Wow. Excuse me, I'm so sorry.
-  He's lying to you.\N- Jeff?
Your son.
He's lying. And I think you know it.
How's your essay?
- Marinating. This is part of my process.\N- Oh? Oh, really?
- I think your guy got away.\N- Thanks, I'm on it.
- You seem really stressed.\N-  I agree.
- You're stretched too thin.\N- Yeah, thanks for the tip.
- That was bad.\N-  I know.
- What's really going on with this kid?\N- I don't know!
- Oh! Hey!\N-  Boom!
- Spider-Man.\N-  Officer Morales! I mean:
-  Officer Morales.\N-  This is not what it looks like.
- Hey! Hey!\N-  Officer--
My kid goes here, man!
This is fun.
I'm on the PTA. You know how many\Nlemon bars I gotta bake for that?
-  You left in the middle of a fight.\N-  I did not. It was at the end.
-  Are you serious?\N-  It was inconsiderate, super rude.
And a little cocky.
Yeah, you got me agreeing\Nwith the bad guy right now.
"Bad guy"?\NHe's barely a villain of the week.
What'd you call me?
- You realise I'm right here.\N- Come on!
...is under control.
-  Unbelievable.\N-  Wow.
Of course we'd end up back here.
You know, you are just like my son.
I am? I--\NThat's so silly. Imagine that.
-  Back where it all started!\N-  Look out!
The crucible of our connection!
Don't try to wow me with big words.
I do the crossword every day.
-  Is it all coming back to you?\N-  What are you talking about?
The creation event.
What?
- Ah!
- Yeah.\N- Hey, we got cut off.
This is our son we're talking about.\NNothing is more important than family.
I'm kind of in the middle of something.
Destiny brought us here.
- You see now, don't you?\N- I really don't.
I am your nemesis.
Dude, you are not.
You missed.\NYou can't contain the Spot. Ow!
You really don't remember\Nwhat you did to me?
- What I did for you?\N-  Uh... No.
I worked at Alchemax.
I ran a test on this collider
that brought a spider here\Nfrom another dimension.
- Forty-two.\N-  Its home dimension.
It escaped. And it bit you.
My spider made you Spider-Man.
- What?\N- You ran through the cafeteria.
- He took a bagel!\N- You hit me with a bagel.
I've hit a lot of different villains\Nwith a lot of different food.
You make your flippy, little sassy jokes,
and everyone loves them.
But no one knows what it feels like\Nto be on the other side of them.
I'm just trying to lighten the mood.
I created you.
You created me.
Spider-Man, why did you create that guy?
I didn't. He's talking crazy.
I was in this collider room\Nwhen you blew it up!
Because of you...
I lost my job, my life,
my face!
My family won't even look at me.
I made you into a hero.
You made me into this!
Look at me! You did this to me!
Look at me! I'll make you respect me!
Ah! Ow!
I am your neme--
Well, where'd he go?
He kicked his own butt.
You know we're supposed\Nto catch the bad guys, right?
I always do.
- Usually.
- Gutierrez! Get the crane, man.\N-  Yes, sir!
This here is why nobody likes us, man.
-  "Us"?\N- I am trying to do right out here.
- I'm trying too.\N- You need to be a better role model.
I'm a great role model.
Hey, Gutierrez, you can cancel the crane.
I swear, I'll quit my job!
- Do you wanna talk about it?\N- Are you crazy?!
Well, men of your generation\Nignore their mental health too long.
Oh, boy.
What am I even doing?
'Cause no matter what I do,\Nsomeone always thinks I'm blowing it.
I know the feeling.
So your son.
How's he doing?\NYou think he's gonna figure it all out?
- Honestly?\N- Yeah.
- He's a good kid.\N- Yeah?
It's scary.\NHe says these things that are so smart.
Cool. Well, I should probably--
And then he does these things\Nthat are so stupid.
I just don't want him to mess it up.
Maybe get off the kid's ass.
- I'm sorry, what?\N- What? What? I don't know.
And I hate\Nthat he's not being honest with me.
Maybe he's scared to talk to you.
Why would anyone be scared to talk to me?
I don't-- I don't know.
It's just-- You think you're getting\Npretty good at being a parent.
You think you got it licked.
And then they go and grow up.
I just don't wanna lose him, you know?
Well, as an objective observer\Nwith no skin in the game,
I say you gotta let him\Nspread his wings, man.
- Like this.\N- Yeah.
I don't know.
If this isn't nice, what is?
I should go.
Yeah, and catch that holes guy.
Don't worry. I don't think\Nthat guy's gonna show his face again.
What?
Okay.
I think I kicked myself...
into myself.
Well, this is new.
Hello? Hello? Echo, echo. No echo.
I'm going to put my head in that hole.
- Hello.
Ow! Please! Ow, ow, ow!
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
That was cool.
My holes can take me anywhere.
- Whoop.
Excuse me. Hi.
- Sorry to bug you. I know you're busy.\N- What do you want?
I know it's weird. I came out of nowhere.
But I think I'm becoming\Na transdimensional superbeing.
- So?\N-"So?"
I'm literally splitting\Nthe fabric of space and time.
For you, it's just a Tuesday night.
You're acting like weird stuff like this\Nhappens to you all the time.
Can I have some gum?
Oh! Whoa!
Wow.
The power of the multiverse\Nin the palm of my hand.
My holes aren't a curse!\NThey're the answer!
Can you stop talking about your holes?
You're making everyone uncomfortable.
No, no, no. You're gonna love this.\NLook, look, look.
I'm out of spots,\Nwouldn't you know it. Uh...
As you were, gentlemen.
I'm coming for you, Spider-Man!
Take this one step at a time.
Does anybody have\Nthe instructions for this building?
- Oh, no.
Tomorrow morning, Spider-Man,\Npage one, with a decent picture.
- You're right, boss.\N- Shut up.
- Uh-huh.\N- Get out of here!
You got it, boss. I'm on it.
I need a raise.
Miguel, it's Peter. We got an anomaly.
Thank you, Peter. You're one of our best.
- Jess, who's on this?
There you go.
- Have you seen Miles?\N- No.
Nope.
- Have you seen Miles?
- What are you doing?\N-  Speech!
- Okay, everybody.\N- No. I'm terrible at speeches.
Oh, dear God, no.
Rio, come on.
Um... Hi.
And I want you to know,\Nno matter what,
even though we've had our ups and downs,
- I'm so proud of you today, and every day.\N-  Hey.
- Parentheses. Mostly. LOL.\N- Hey.
Hey, Mr Spider-Man,\Nit won't fit on one cake.
Can't you write smaller?
Can't you write shorter?
Come again!
What else can I say about Jeff?
That he was almost 10 pounds as a baby.\NI know you're gonna be embarrassed.
He almost killed his mother.\NLook at those shoulders.
- Oh, no. Okay. That's it.\N-  A big baby.
- Okay, okay.\N- Oh, my God.
He's so funny.
I'll take the mic.\NNo more mics for you, okay?
- Thank you, Rio, for that.\N-  Where is that kid?
I didn't always know\Nwhat I wanted to do in life.
I was pulled in a lot\Nof different directions when I was young.
Me and my brother came up\Nin this neighbourhood.
Just a couple of knuckleheads\Nrunning the streets.
It is I, the Armadillo-- [grunts] Oh!
You guys used\Nto chase us out of your stores.
And now, if you can believe it,\Nit's my job to look out for you.
-And then I had a kid.\N- Stop, thief!
And everything changed for the better.
Oh, no.
I don't even know about giving a toast\N'cause I should be toasting you all.
No, no, no!
So to my brother,\Nwho we miss every single day.
He's definitely up there\Nlaughing at me right now.
They're making me captain, bro.
To my wife, mi amor.
I can't even start\Nbecause I'll never stop.
Have to take the mic from me.
And to my son...
The reason that I do any of this\Nin the first place.
I love you, Miles.
And I will always, always be here for you.
Benny, man. Come on, drop the beat!
I'm gonna kill that kid.
Hey! Congrats, Jeff!
- Hey! Hey, hey.\N- Thank you for coming.
- Hey, Miles. Where have you been?\N- What's up, man?
- You keeping your head up at that school?\N-  Oh, yeah, you bet.
Hola, Miles! Hi.
- Your parents have been looking for you.\N- I don't know why.
- I've just been here the whole time.\N- Oye.
- Ah! Hi.\N- You were supposed to be here at 5.
- I know.\N- You disrespected your dad.
-  Yup. Mm-hm.\N- Missed his beautiful toast.
Come on. Did you even see the cakes?\NThere's some heartfelt messages on them.
That's not what I meant.
Your dad studied for eight months.
Nine. It was like giving birth.
- No, it wasn't.\N- Of course not.
You made us sit in that office\Nand talk to that lady without you.
- There was an emergency.\N- What, a graffiti emergency?
A partying-with-some-friends-\NI've-never-met emergency?
Explain yourself.
Sounds like\Nyou're explaining it pretty well.
- That's funny. Jeff, we got a funny son.\N- I'm not laughing.
- I don't feel grown-up.\N-  Wow, this is a cool shirt.
Okay! Okay, okay.\NHave you checked out the spread?
- Oye!\N- Ah!
Who you running around with?
- Just--\N- Is it Ganke? I never liked him.
Yes, you did.
- He calls me by my first name.\N- Ugh. We hate that.
- I have more friends than just Ganke.\N- Like who?
Well, there's-- There's Peter.
You know, uh, but he left town.
Um, there's-- There's Gwanda.
You know, she also left town.
- Miles, dame un break.\N- Is that Spanglish?
Has it ever occurred to you\Nthat maybe I'm just doing benign, private,
unremarkable things\Nwhen I'm not with you guys?
- Nope.\N- Never.
I am 15 years old.\NI am basically an adult.
- Oh, right.\N- You don't have a driver's licence.
- Neither does Mom!\N- We live in New York
and never plan to leave.
- It's my life.\N- It's not your life.
It's mine and your father's\Nand your abuelos' y abuelas',
who put you in this spot\Nthat I'd give anything to be in.
All right. Whatever, whatever.
"Whatever"?
- Wow.\N-"Whatever"?
- Do I get to say it? Please tell me I can.\N- Say it.
- You're grounded!\N- What?
- Oh, yeah!\N- For how long?
- A month!\N- Dad. Mom, are you--? Seriously?
Yeah, dead serious.
- You don't understand.\N- You are right.
I have no idea what's going on with you!\NSo why don't you tell me?
- Just listen to me!
Okay, champ, you got it. Go for it.\NSay whatever you wanna say.
What do you got to tell me so bad?
You know what? Never mind.
All right, great, walk away.
Because now you got two months!
That was good, right?
Two months.
I'm Spider-Man. I'm not grounded.
Miles!
You got a minute?
Oh! Whoa!
- How did you get--?
How did you get--? How have you been?
Uh, I've been good.
I've been-- Yeah, just great. Look at you.
You, uh-- You grew, huh?
- Had a little growth spurt?\N- Uh, yeah. Your hair has gotten pinker.
- Is this the room you grew up in?\N- It is. Um...
- But my dorm room is very adult.
Cool. Yeah, no, I used to play with these\Nwhen I was younger too.
- Uh, that's a collectible.\N- I used to have this one.
- An extremely rare, highly sought--\N- Why is it still in the package?
Eee! Um...
That's fine.
- Are these your drawings? They're good.\N- Hey. What? No.
Wow, there's so many.
Missed you too.
So, what are you doing here?
I mean, I thought I'd never see you again.
Wanna get out of here?
I'm grounded.
Bummer.
Is Spider-Man grounded?
Um...
I mean, I...
Miles?
Your dad's ready to listen now.
That's three months!
Wait, hold on.
There's an elite society\Nwith all the best Spider-People in it?
- Okay, so there's this lady, Jess Drew.\N- Uh-huh?
- She rides a motorcycle.\N- Motorcycle?
Oh, my gosh,\NI'm learning so much from her.
Oh, yeah. I've learned a lot of stuff too.
I've levelled up my whole thing. See?
-  Oh, yeah?\N- Yeah.
-  Let's see it, then.\N- Let's go.
Thread the needle.
Whoa!
Easy.
And Miguel.
- The whole thing was his idea.\N-  Right.
And who's Miguel?
Oh, he's like a\Nninja-vampire-Spider-Man but a good guy.
A vampire good guy.\NI'd pay good money to see that.
- So how long ago did they invite you?\N- Only like a few months ago.
-"Months" is kind of a long time.\N-  Okay, this one counts for two.
Ha, ha!
Look at you.
Look at me.
Keep the change.
- So this club.\N- Look at that dum-dum.
What kind of stuff do you do?
Guy in the stripes, ten points.
We're trying to keep the multiverse\Nfrom collapsing.
I thought we did that already.
Like, last week we had this mission\Nto some Shakespeare dimension.
-  What?\N- And Hobie and I just, like--
-  Who's Hobie?\N-  Oh, my gosh, you would love him.
He lets me crash\Nin his dimension sometimes.
What does that mean,\Nyou stay overnight or...?
Anyway, they're pretty strict\Nabout where I go,
or I really would have come\Nto see you sooner.
Right. So, uh-- So why'd you come now?
Don't do that.
Hey, Gw-- Uh, Gwen?
Where'd you go?
Where did she go?
-  Ah!\N- Oh, hey. There you are.
- What were you doing?\N- Waiting for you.
No, it's not the Greek burger place.
- This is a cool thinking spot.\N-  Right?
Who needs a treadmill when you have\Nthe Williamsburgh Bank Building?
- So, uh, you and your dad.
You still haven't talked?
What exactly would we talk about?
"Hey, Dad, how have\Nthe last few months been?
You still think\NI murdered my best friend?"
I don't know.
I mean, my parents--\NI mean, maybe if I told them--
Don't.
Trust me on that.
Well...
Maybe some things\Nare supposed to be just for us.
Hm.
That's a nice way to think about it.
I'm just a really\Nemotionally intelligent guy.
Beyond my years.
It really is always so great\Nto talk to you.
- Yeah?\N- Yeah.
I mean, how many people\Ncan you talk to about this stuff?
You don't even know.
What?
You're the only friend\NI've ever really made after Peter died.
Other than Hobie, right?
- That's different.\N- Yeah? How's that?
I don't know.
You and me, it's...
We're the same.
In the important ways, you know?
In every other universe,\NGwen Stacy falls for Spider-Man.
And in every other universe,
it doesn't end well.
Well, there's a first time\Nfor everything, right?
- Mmm! Oh, wow. Feelings make me hungry.\N- Oh, yeah,
these plátanos are\Njust deep-fried feelings.
She looks old enough to vote.
I bet she doesn't even speak Spanish.
Well, qué barbaridad.
This keeps you from glitching\Nin other dimensions?
Yeah. Pretty cool.
What's it gonna take\Nfor Miguel O'Hara to notice Miles Morales?
I'll put in a good word.
I'm just saying, if I had a watch,\NI could come with you.
- Miles, look--\N- I did save the multiverse.
It's a really small, elite strike force.
I can turn invisible.\NI have, like, electric powers.
- There aren't a lot of slots.\N- Think about it.
Ah, right.
Look, if it was up to me, you--
I know. I know, I know.
Oh, no. No, no.
- Don't do that. Miles!\N- All right.
- It's, uh, really delicate.\N- Geez.
Sorry. I didn't mean to, um, snap.
Okay. All right. I'm sorry.
- Hello! Hi.
- Oh, boy.\N- I'm Miles's mom.
Rio! Hi! I've heard so much about you.
You're using my first name. Okay.
This is nice.\NWe found it in Miles's room, so...
- I guess you must've been there, huh?\N- And you must be Jeff.
She called me Jeff.\NThat's very sweet. "Jeff."
You must mean Lieutenant Morales.
Soon to be Captain Morales.
Ah! Captain.
Gwanda and I are friends from school.
- Yeah, we were just catching up.\N- Oh...
Don't take him from me.
Mom.
I'm just kidding.\NHe's grounded, so you can't.
- Don't break his heart.\N- Mom!
- Alpha Squad, Zero Red Spider Alert.\N- Shoot, I have to go.
- Really?\N- Yeah, I forgot to get my steps in.
Really, really wish I could stay longer.
I'm sorry.
Goodbye.
Yeah, bye.
I can hear you being quiet, Mom.
I, um...
I hope I didn't ice your game, man.
No one my age says those words\Nin that order, Mom.
It's just hard to see my little man\Nnot be my little boy all the time.
Yeah.
Papá, you know you can tell me anything.
Well...
I'm...
I'm sorry I was late.
Go.
She seems like a nice girl.
- Is this a trick?\N- It's not a trick.
Geez.
What are you--?
Let me fix you. Just...
For years I've been taking care\Nof this little boy, right?
Making sure he's loved,
that he feels like he belongs\Nwherever he wants to be.
He wants to go out into the world\Nand do great big things.
And what I worry about most...
is they won't look out for you like us.
They won't root for you like us.
So here's the deal.
Wherever you go from here,
you have to promise to take care\Nof that little boy for me.
Make sure he never forgets\Nwhere he came from.
And he never doubts that he's loved.
And he never lets anyone at those big,\Nfancy places he's gonna be in
tell him that he doesn't belong there.
And when he comes home,\Nand he better come home...
you're gonna be early,
and you're gonna be holding\Na normal, nice cake.
Yeah, okay.
You gotta promise, Miles.
I promise.
Just...
- don't get lost.\N- Mm-hm. Okay.
All right.
Cool.
Now go. Get out of here.
And when you come back,\Nyou're still grounded.
- Ha, ha!
Yeah, I'm smiling like it's a joke,\Nbut it's true.
Yeah, I figured.
See you later.
With a cake.
Shoot.
Whoa, whoa, hey, hey, the car!
Oh, shoot, shoot, shoot.
- Show me what happened.\N-  Replay commencing.
Spots. That's the thing.\NI need more spots!
Ha! Oh, my gosh. It was right under\Nwhere my nose would've been.
I just need a little bit more\Ndimensional juice or whatever.
- Shoot.\N- Shoot!
Never came up with a good name.\NBranding was never my strong suit.
The city power line\Nto my micro collider prototype
could generate a little more\Nconcentrated dark energy.
Shoot.
This is what I love about science!
Shoot!
I just need enough to get me somewhere\Nwith a full-size collider.
And, Spider-Man, I'll make you pay\Nfor everything you took away from me.
All right, this is gonna work.
Or vaporise me\Nand everything in this building,
which would not be good.
- Shoot.\N- Shoot.
Oh, man.
Replay complete.
Why, why, why?
- Gwen, Gwen, Gwen!\N- Gwen. Hi.
Whatcha doing?
Nothing. Uh, good. All good.\NYeah, everything's good.
Bye.
Where's the bad guy\Nyou were supposed to monitor?
He just stepped out for a moment.
- Dude!\N- He's just some villain of the week.
- LYLA!\N- Oh! We don't need--
Tracking...
Hey, look, I got him. Nope, never mind.
Hold on. Slippery guy.
- Did you go see your little friend?\N- What? No.
-  Miles?\N- I mean...
Are you kidding me?
- Only briefly. From afar.\N- How far?
Like, you know, about this:
- About this far.\N- That's way too close.
Girl!
Look, I had to know how he was.
- I honestly can't with you.\N- I know I messed up, okay?
He can't be part of this.
I know.
- I'll never see him again. All right?\N-  No kidding.
- Hey, guys? He's making his own portals.\N- What?
He can jump wherever he wants.\NHe could be a total canon killer.
You said he was the villain of the week.\NDo you know how bad this is for you?
Every dimension he stops at\Nhas an Alchemax.
- What's he up to, Gwen?\N- I don't know.
He's making himself more powerful\Nso he can beat me.
Amazing. My star pupil, everyone.
I'll get him, okay? I can get backup.
If Miguel finds out I let you come--
Don't tell Miguel. He'll kick me out and--
What if he sends me home?
I got him. Earth-50101.
What do you wanna do?
You never made a mistake?
Never got too close to someone?
I did.
But I got over it.
Alert the local Spider.\NTell him Gwen will meet him there.
I'm on it.
- Thank you. I won't let you down again.\N- Okay. You're welcome. Shut up.
You got an hour to fix this.
Or I can't help you.
Goodbye, Miles.
- Sorry. Congratulations!
You see that? This is incredible.
- I'm like a new person.\N-  Where did you go?
In the mirror,\NI wouldn't recognise myself.
-  Stay still.\N- I'd envy that person I was looking at.
-  I have eyes on the anomaly.\N-  Try getting hands on him.
Stop hovering. You're hovering.
Hello, pardon me, locals.
Wow, four on there. That's very dangerous.
That looks good.
- Which way to Alchemax? Oh!
It's a place with a big collider--
- Hey, cow guy! "Moo-ve" over!\N-  That's the best you could do?
-  Gwen! I'm here to help!\N- Miles, are you--?
Whoopsie-daisy.\NYou weren't expecting that, were you?
-  Oh, no!\N-  Neither was I. I'm in the zone!
-  I got you!\N- Did you follow me?
No, I just saw where you went\Nand went there without you knowing.
- You're not supposed to be here!\N- What are you talking about? I'm helping--
No! No, no, no!
Whoa!
I shouldn't have ever come to see you.
Dang.
Hey, who's the new guy?
Hey, Pav.\NHe's Miles and he wasn't invited.
Oh!\NYou weren't invited and you came anyway?
- Right?\N- New guy must be in love with you.
-  Okay, whoa.\N-  No.
- I'm not.\N- I'm very good at reading people.
-  He's not.\N-  Who are you?
-  Glad you asked, new guy.\N- I'm not a new guy.
My name is Pavitr Prabhakar,\Nand for the past six months--
Six? And even he got a watch?
- Yeah, uh...\N- Being Spider-Man is so easy.
I wake up, skip the workout,
because I'm naturally buff\Nand I don't wanna get too big.
Do almost nothing with my amazing hair.
You don't use any product at all?
Just coconut oil, prayer, some genetics.
Then I swing by school.\NDon't really have to try, but I do anyway.
Fight a few bad guys,\Nfeed a few street dogs,
quick break for a cup of chai\Nwith my Maya Auntie--
- I love chai tea.\N- What did you just say?
"Chai tea"?
"Chai" means "tea," bro.\NYou're saying "tea" tea.
Would I ask you for a "coffee" coffee\Nwith "cream" cream?
I'm so sorry.
Then I hang out\Nwith my girlfriend, Gayatri.
She's an extremely classy teenager.
Hey, girl. Tonight, I was thinking--
Hello, Police Inspector Singh.
This is your daughter. I do not know her.
To top it off, I live in the best possible\NSpider-Man city, Mumbattan.
Quick tour. This is where the traffic is,\Nthis is where the traffic is.
Traffic here too. This is where\Nthe British stole all of our stuff. Whoa!
-  Hello, Spider-Man.\N-  Hi.
-  Hey.\N-  Not you.
You talking to him or me or him?
-  Think he means me.\N-  Yeah. Him.
I got this, guys.
- Huh?\N- Wow. How are you?
- Can you tell I levelled up my game?
I'm on a journey of self-improvement.
And you came to India.
That's a Western culture cliché.\NDon't Eat, Pray, Love me, bro.
I did not mean it like that.
Let me guess, you're gonna ask me\Nabout saffron and cardamom
and naan bread,\Nwhich is the same as saying "bread" bread,
which is the same as saying "chai tea."
-  Oh, I love chai tea.\N-  No!
Come on, man! I think maybe\Nwe got off on the wrong foot.
Let's just talk about this.
Fine. You made me feel empty,\Nlike I had a hole inside of me.
We all have holes.
But now I found out\Nwhat to fill that hole up with.
More holes!
That doesn't make any sense!
It will.
I'm okay. I'm good.
- Don't worry.\N-  We won't.
This romantic tension is so palpable.
If Spot gets more holes...
-  Will they, won't they?\N- ...he'll be unstoppable!
- We can't let him get to--\N-  Alchemax?
See? How can you guys even concentrate?
Hey, does he know about Hobie?
- What should I know about Hobie?\N- Oh, looks like he did not know.
Boop.
Go away. Go away.\NSee you later. Thanks for coming.
Would you please deactivate\Nthis strong barrier?
It can't be turned off\Nuntil the collider sequence is complete.
The collider sequence? Oh, man.
-  You need to stop!\N-  You don't know what you're doing!
I'm about to be so much more\Nthan a villain of the week.
I'm sorry I called you that, okay?\NYou're a great villain.
Oh, not yet, I'm not.
-  Initialising collider.\N- No!
How's it going now?
Great. Anyone got any ideas?
Oh, I have so many, but none for this.
Stand back.\NI've been working on something new.
-  How long does this usually take?\N-  Just give me a second.
Do you want us to do something,\Nor do we just stand here?
Are you charging it, or--?
No. I'm absorbing it\Nso I can shoot it back.
-  Looks like you're charging.\N-  Does this have a name?
Hold your questions\Nuntil I'm done breaking this!
Just let me do this!
Oi, oi!
- Hobie!\N-  Hobie, my guy!
-  Hobie?\N-  Look at that, another one.
I love how many different variations\Nof you guys there are.
- Man-like, Pav! Big stepper! Yeah, mate!\N- What's this dude saying?
It's English for "We get\Nalong great, and we're close friends."
Is this the younger from 1610?
Do you understand this guy?
Hobie, thanks for breaking the shield!
I loosened it.
Bit of advice.\NUse the palm, not just your fingers.
What's up with your suit?\NIs he bleeding from his armpits?
Miles, Hobie. Hobie, Miles.
Hi. I've never heard of you\Nbecause Gwen barely ever mentions you.
A'ight, my name's Hobie, Hobie Brown.\NI was bitten by a--
Wouldn't you like to know?\NYou know what I mean?
For the last three years, I've been\Nthe one and only-- Wait, wait, wait.
You think I'm gonna show you\Nmy secret identity? Come out of it.
That is, when I'm not playing shows,\Nantagonizing fascists,
staging unpermitted political actions\Nslash performance-art pieces,
or having a laugh at the pub\Nwith the mandem.
I'm not a role model.\NI was briefly a runway model.
I hate the a.m. I hate the PM.\NI hate labels.
I'm not a hero\Nbecause calling yourself a hero
makes you a self-mythologizing,\Nnarcissistic autocrat.
Come on! I thought you hated labels.
Gwendy, you left your jumper\Naround my place.
- What's a jumper?\N-  It's a sweater.
- How many sweaters do you have?\N- That's not mine, I'm sure.
-  And your toothbrush.\N-  Wait, what?
-  Are those my Chucks?
-  Y'all make a heck of a team.\N-  I don't believe in teams.
Aren't you in a band?
I don't believe in consistency.
This guy's killing me.
This is gonna be good for us, Spider-Man.
You and me, we're finally\Ngonna live up to our potential.
You'll finally have\Na villain worth fighting.
And I won't be just a joke to you!
You're not a joke!
- Right, gang?\N-  Absolutely.
-  Completely unamusing!\N-  I don't believe in comedy!
Just kidding!
See? No one here thinks you're a joke!
-  They won't after this.\N-  No!
Wow. That was another easy adventure\Nfor Spider-Man.
-  No, no, no!\N-  No, no, no!
I'm coming!
What was that?
Our future.
I'm gonna take everything from you,\Nlike you took everything from me.
What?
See you back home, Spider-Man.
Miles. Miles!
You okay? We gotta go.
Oi, oi, liven up, mate.\NNo time to get dizzy.
Everyone, chalo, chalo!
We'll clear the path.\NYou slow down that building.
I'll do it.\NBut not because you told me to.
Everybody, run!
Watch out!
Gayatri!
Gayatri! No!
Gwen, heads up.
Markers are predicting\Nan incoming canon event.
So tread carefully.
I'm on it.
Somebody, help!
- Hurry, everyone! This way, quickly!\N-  Help!
Inspector Singh!
I can do both!
-  I got him, I got him!\N-  Miles!
Don't worry.\NThread the needle, ring the bell, right?
- It's too dangerous.\N- I'll be okay, I promise.
Miles!
No! No.
You're all right.
I promised.
Are you okay? I was so worried.
I mean, you seem like a nice young woman\Nthat I do not know.
Gayatri!
Not bad, right?
Right.
I've never seen him so emotional.
Excellent job.
Man-like, Miles! My guy!
Easy.
So, what do you think?
What I always think.
You're amazing.
We make a good team. Yeah?
Yeah.
Guys, what's that?
It's a metaphor for capitalism.
It's a lot worse than that.
Okay, guys, secure the area,\Nclear all civilians,
and let's contain this quantum hole.
Hey, I'm Miles.\NWe met before, when I was invisible.
I know who you are.
Is everything going to be okay?
Okay, let me explain.
Miguel wants you back at HQ.
- Miles was just about to head out.\N- All of you.
- I don't follow orders, neither does he.\N- I'm invited to HQ? Whoo!
How are you even cooler under your mask?
I was this cool the whole time.
Hey, over here.
Yo, this place is wild.
-  Any sign of Spot?\N-  Let me ask.
Anybody spot Spot?
- Oh, so funny. Anybody else got jokes?\N- Now that you mention it.
Well, you know what they say,\Nwe need to run a spot check.
-  This is unbelievable.
- This is the lobby.\N- Oh.
Welcome to Spider-Society.
It's a bit much, innit?
What happened to that small,\Nelite strike team?
A lot of these are part-time.
Gwendy, how much have you told him, hm?\NAbout his place in all this?
A little.
- Maybe not enough.\N- Here.
My own watch!
It's a day pass.\NThis just keeps you from...
...doing that.
-  Hey, Gwen.\N- Hey, Peter.
Hey, I'm Miles.
-  Hey, Gwen.\N- Hey, Peters.
I'm a new recruit.
Peter, take a team to the transport deck\Nto help deal with this Spot mess.
- I wouldn't call it a mess.
- More like a success in progress.\N- Ben, I need--
Sorry, I can't talk right now.\NI'm thinking about my past.
Actually, we need you here\Nfor some reason.
That was a particularly harrowing memory.
- Is he okay?
- Ah!\N- Howdy. Name's Web-Slinger.
- Why does the horse need a mask?\N-  To conceal her face.
Giddy up!
-  Who is in these laser cages?
Anomalies. Folks who wound up\Nin the wrong dimension.
We kick their butts and send them home.
They're not very interesting.
- We got a bunch of Doc Ocks.\N- That's interesting.
A Moosterio. Ms Sterio.
- Video game guy.\N-  I love video games!
- Another video game guy.\N- Are you talking to me?
Typeface.
- Go to Helvetica, Spider-Man!\N- Bold.
An interesting Kraven, a boring Rhino.
A Prowler.
- Prowler?\N-  Not your Prowler.
Hey.
- It's rude to stare.\N- Caught that one myself.
- I slipped.\N- You? I did all the work.
How many missions\Nhave you been on together?
- Not that many.\N- Couple dozen.
That's cool. Sorry.
- I'm Spider-Man.\N- Oh, no way! All of us are.
- Can we just keep moving?\N- Whoa, whoa, whoa. What are you?
I'm an avatar.
My body is back in my parents' dimension,
chilling in a gaming chair\Nand eating Fritos.
Right, because you don't listen.
Here is better.
I hear that.
What does that do?
Apart from having a great name?
- The Go Home Machine.\N- What'd I say, eh?
I voted against it.
It detects whatever dimension\Nyour DNA is from
and sends you there.
It's super humane and not creepy.
See you, dawg. Don't come back.
We should go.\NWe don't wanna keep the boss waiting.
- See you around?\N- Let's go!
- Good luck out there, man.\N- Okay, bye!
Miguel sounds hangry.
He likes those empanadas\Nfrom the cafeteria.
Don't ask me why.
My name is Miguel O'Hara.
I'm this dimension's one\Nand only Spider-Man.
At least, I was.
But I'm not like the others.
I don't always like what I have to do.
But I know I have to be the one to do it.
I've given up too much to stop now.
Whoa, yo.
Bet this doesn't even do anything.
Maybe it did\Nbefore you ripped it out of a wall.
It's propaganda, bruv.\NTo distract you from the truth.
And what's that?
I ain't got a Scooby Doo.\NThat's what they want.
- Why you wanna be part of this lot?\N-  To get a watch.
- Make your own watch.\N- Pssh.
Bet you got a nice setup, eh?\NNice parents.
They're fine.\NI mean, we got in a fight, but...
They just want what's best for me, so...
- That's a bloody shame.\N- Why?
'Cause you're not ready\Nfor everybody else.
-  We did it this time!\N-  Okay, okay, mija.
Good job.
Listen to me, bruv. Whole point\Nof being Spider-Man is your independence.
Being your own boss.\NYou don't need all this.
- Then why are you here?\N- Looking out for my drummer, is all.
I want to be in a band. I--
I wanna see my friends,\Nand I need a watch to do that.
Guys, come on.
All right. Squashed.
Don't enlist till you know\Nwhat war you're fighting.
Yeah, I know it's slow.
But it's his thing.
Miguel O'Hara, meet Miles Morales.
Hey!
I speak Spanish.
-  I'm excited to get going.\N-  Oh. Great.
- I have new ideas on how to catch Spot.\N- Oh. Wow. Uh-huh.
He just wants to be\Ntaken seriously, like we all do. Whoa!
He's worried about Spot.
I'll worry about Spot!
- What did I do?\N- Miguel! It's not his fault.
- Fault? Hold up.\N- You blew another hole in the multiverse!
- He doesn't know any better.\N- I do know what-- Not know what?
But you did, Gwen.
And you--\NI'm just gonna try to ignore you.
- I just can't. I can't even.\N- I ain't even here.
Or here.
- What's happening?\N-  Hey, Miguel!
Come on, go easy on the kid.
- He had a terrible teacher.
He had no chance.
- Peter!\N- Oh, boy.
Humbling-Reality Spider-Man has arrived.
- Miles!\N- Dude!
Don't be afraid of my friend Miguel.\NHe just looks scary. He's got no bite.
-  Peter.\N- You're growing up on me. You look great.
- You look solid, you know. You look good.\N- Define "solid."
What happened?\NYou bleeding from the armpits?
- Peter, you--\N- Don't worry, we'll get you a new suit.
Peter, you gotta tell them--
- Wait. What is that?\N-  Mayday!
- You have a baby!\N- I have a baby.
This is crazy.
Don't forget to keep\Nyour little day pass on, honey.
Oh, you have one too.\NI didn't know they made those for adults.
- Give me a second. Mayday!\N- The kid's an anarchist.
I'm coming up to get you.\NHere I come. Don't move.
I got you. I knew I was gonna regret\Nmaking her that web shooter.
I shouldn't have done it.\NThat's an actual mistake.
- You wanna see pictures?\N- She's right there.
- Look at this pic!\N- Oh, you've got them.
- She's incredible.\N- Yup.
This is her funny face.\NThat's her mad face.
This one is the studious one.
Watch out,\Nthe next one you're gonna crack up.
Miguel's gonna die.\NMiguel, look at this one.
I'm trying to hold\Na serious adult conversation.
You're the only Spider-Man\Nwho isn't funny.
- We're supposed to be funny.\N- The fate of the multiverse--
You always lose me with that.
You say, "The fate of the multiverse,"\Nand my brain dies.
Do you guys smell that?\NMayday took a crap.
- Yup. She's a Parker.\N-  Miles.
That's what happens\Nwhen a Parker eats an avocado.
- You disrupted a canon event.\N- Canon event?
The kid wasn't thinking.\NThat's not how he works.
That's insulting.
Taking a crap on the establishment.\NI salute you.
Wait, what are you upset about?\NI saved those people.
And that's the problem.
- LYLA, do the thing.\N- Huh? What thing?
What do you mean, "What thing?"\NThe information-explainy thing.
Okay.
What's this?
This is everything.
Can you be more specific?
Can you not talk for a second?
Yeah, yeah, I--
And this here?
This is all of us.
All of our lives woven together
in a beautiful web of life and destiny.
The Spider-Verse.
Spider-Verse.
That's stupid.
It's called\Nthe Arachnohumanoid Polymultiverse.
Which sounds stupid too, I guess.
And these nodes where the lines converge?
They are the canon.
Chapters that are a part\Nof every Spider's story every time.
Some good.
Some bad.
Some very bad.
Just keep going.
Uncle Aaron.
This one, Event ASM-90.
A police captain close to Spider-Man dies,
saving a kid from falling rubble\Nduring a battle with an archnemesis.
Captain Stacy.
I'm so sorry.
No.
That happened to you?
And me.
Ey. What of it?
That's how the story is supposed to go.
Canon events are the connections\Nthat bind our lives together.
But those connections can be broken.
That's why anomalies are so dangerous.
Inspector Singh's death was a canon event.
You weren't supposed to be there.
And you weren't supposed to save him.
- That's why Gwen tried to stop you.\N-  Miles!
I thought you were trying to save me.
I was. I...
I was doing both.
And now, Miles,\Nbecause you changed the story,
Pavitr's dimension is unravelling.
If we're lucky, we can stop it.
We haven't always been lucky.
That wasn't me. That was the Spot.
It's what happens\Nwhen you break the canon.
How do you know?
Because I broke it once myself.
I found a world where I had a family.
Where I was happy.
At least, a version of me was.
And that version of myself was killed.
So I replaced him.
I thought it was harmless.
But I was wrong.
Daddy? Dad.
Daddy, no!
Isn't that right, Peter?
Yeah.
You break enough canon,\Nsave enough captains...
and we could lose everything.
My dad is about to be captain.
No.
I'm gonna take everything from you...
- like you took everything from me.\N-  I'm coming!
Spot does it.
He kills him.
When does it happen?
- When does it happen?\N- In two days.
When he's sworn in.
That's what the model says.
I'm sorry, Miles.
Send me home.
I can't do that. Not now.
What am I supposed to do?\NJust let him die?
What about your dad?
He's a captain, right?
Yeah.
And that's it?
You aren't gonna do anything about it?
Okay, what about Uncle Ben?
That have been okay if you knew\Nand you just let it play out?
If not for Uncle Ben,
most of us wouldn't be here, Miles.
And all the good we did, it...
It wouldn't have been done.
So we're just supposed to let people die
because some algorithm says that\Nthat's supposed to happen?
You realise how messed up\Nthat sounds, right?
You have a choice\Nbetween saving one person
and saving an entire world.
Every world.
I can do both. Spider-Man always--
Not always.
Miles, we all want to live the life\Nwe wish we had.
Believe me, I have tried.
And the harder I tried,\Nthe more damage I did.
You can't have it all, kid.
Being Spider-Man is a sacrifice.
That's the job.
That's what you signed up for.
Miles.
Peni?
What is this?
Is this is an intervention or something?
We know it's hard.
But it's the truth, Miles.
Is that why you're here?\NTo let me down easy?
It worked last time,\Nwhy not run it back, huh?
- Hey, hold on. Hold on.\N- You were right, Gwen.
- You should've never come to see me.\N- Kid, look at--
Stop calling me that.
- There we go.\N- Hobie, not helping.
- Good.\N- Miles, please understand.
You can't ask me not to save my father.
I'm not asking.
Just give him a second, please.
- This is a great look.\N- Don't! Stop it!
If we let him leave, he'll only do\Nmore damage. We both know that.
Little man. Peter Pan. Palms.
Just need to hold you a few days.\NSorry it had to end like this, kid.
I said not to call me that!
- Miles!
All right.
I'm sorry for doing this.\NThis is bad parenting.
Just for the record, I quit.
-  Huh?\N-  Uh...
All stations,
drop what you're doing\Nand stop Spider-Man.
- You?\N- You?
- Me?\N- Me?
Miles! Miles Morales!\NHe's entering Sector 4!
- Is that him?\N- Do I, uh, have web on my face?
What's the deal?
Miles! He's right there. He's right in--
- Turn around!\N- I don't see anything, boss.
Can this day get any damn weirder?
Wow! I guess it can.
- Whoa!\N- Sorry!
And then I looked at my uncle, and...
Uh, let me guess. He died?
Whoa!
On the count of three, draw.
One-- You didn't wait for three!
Hey, Miguel!
Can you take a photo of this?\NIt's her first chase.
Boo.
-  Miles?\N-  Hi.
- I'm a huge fan of your work.\N- Thanks.
Do you think Spider-People too often use\Ncomedy as a crutch?
- Uh...\N- Get it? "Crutch"?
- I can do anything he can.
Oh, dang, I pulled something.
Meow!
There's nowhere to run.
My bad, everybody.\NThere was somewhere to run.
-  Stop running!\N- Then stop chasing me!
You're so frustrating.
I know he's your friend,\Nbut it's the only way.
- But my gut says--\N- Then use your head.
I've got you trapped\Nin my well-defined musculature.
So don't even--
Miles.
- No, no. Let me go.\N- It is crazy to run.
Running is the least crazy thing going on.
- Look, I feel bad.\N- Good!
But this is just how stuff works.\NYou're not gonna win here.
Just wait, don't move.\NStop moving so fast.
No!
- Do you wanna hold my baby?\N- What?
Would you just give the baby one squeeze\Nand then we'll talk?
I think it's gonna change our vibe.\NIt's very rejuvenating.
I'm plenty juvenated.
You'll get more so when you go\Nchest-to-chest with this magical child.
You don't get to have\Na heartfelt conversation with me.
Just hold the baby,\Nwe'll see what happens!
You're the reason I had her, okay?
I thought that if I did\Na decent job raising her,
then there was a chance\Nshe was gonna turn out like you.
And that got me excited\Nbecause you are a wonderful person.
- And I like being around you.
Then why didn't you come see me?
Bec--
I couldn't.
I wanted to be with you guys so badly.
But this thing\Nisn't what I thought it was.
Look, bad things are gonna happen.
It makes us who we are.
But good things happen too, you know?
Like you happened.
And she happened.
Hey, I don't...
And you are so bad at holding a baby.
-  We got your location, Peter.\N- Wait, wait. No, no!
You do not have my location. Over.
Send everyone.
No, no, no, Miles, I didn't know.\NI promise you.
Please, man, let's talk about this.
We did.
Good talk.
Get him!
Miles!
- Where does he think he's going?\N-  Don't think he planned this out.
If I hadn't said it before, by the way,
you're a terrible mentor.
He did just beat you,\Nso I'm not a terrible mentor.
You're both equally terrible.\NDoes that settle it?
Stop pretending\Nyou know where you're going!
Oh, I have a plan.\NI just haven't told you yet.
-  Departing for the moon.\N- That's not good.
What are those, claws?
Dude, are you sure you're even Spider-Man?
Are you?
Who do you think you are? Really?
My name is Miles Morales.
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
And I'm pretty sure\Nyou know the rest, jerk!
Hey. What's up, man?
You don't get it. You're an anomaly.
Not if you let me go home.
Snitch!
Everywhere you go, you're an anomaly.
You're the original anomaly.
Miguel!
The spider that gave you\Nyour powers wasn't from your dimension.
It was never supposed to bite you.
Miguel, don't!
There's a world out there\Nwith no Spider-Man to protect them
- because it bit you instead.\N- No.
You're not supposed to be Spider-Man.
No! You're lying. I'm Spider-Man!
You're a mistake!
If you hadn't been bit,\Nyour Peter Parker would have lived.
Instead, he died saving you.
He would've stopped the collider\Nbefore it ever went off.
Spot wouldn't exist.
- And none of this would've happened.\N- Peter.
And all this time, I have been\Nthe only one holding it all together.
-  Miguel, go easy on him!\N- You don't belong here.
You never did.
Let me go.
- Miguel, that's enough.\N- This isn't what we talked about.
You talked about this?
You knew?
You all knew?
I didn't know...
how to tell you.
That's why you never came to see me.
- Miles, it's for your own good.\N- Who decides that?
I'm not a kid, Gwen.
That's exactly what you are.
You're just a kid\Nwho has no idea what he's doing!
Yeah, well,
I did lure hundreds of Spider-People\Naway from your little clubhouse.
What?
I guess he did plan this out.
And I'm about to do this.
Everyone keeps telling me\Nhow my story is supposed to go.
Nah.
I'm gonna do my own thing.
Goodbye, Gwen.
Miles!
I taught him how to do that,
so I gotta be a pretty good mentor\Nto pull that off.
Nope. No. Uh-uh.
That's kind of cute. Oh, no. Mm-mm.
Been there. Done that.
- Huh?
Initialising Go Home Machine.
Dimensional signature identified.
Come on.
No. No.
- Oh, no.\N- No.
What's happening?
The machine activated on its own.
- How is that possible?\N- It isn't.
It's not possible\Nfor the accelerator protocol
to engage without entering a sequence key.
- Okay. Which...?\N- Which it's doing right now.
- How about this?\N- No.
- How about now?\N- You're getting in the way.
Stop him! Now!
What does it look like I'm trying to do?
Do something.
Now!
Miguel.
Miguel, stop!
No!
Okay. Enough.\NIt's not the console's fault.
All he had to do was listen!
- Why didn't he listen?\N- Maybe you weren't hard enough.
- Gwen, don't do it.\N-  You let him go.
- Me?\N- You didn't catch him, Gwen.
- Okay, let's all just take a breath.\N- Peter, you wanna back me up?
Well, okay, Miguel, as a father\Nof a daughter and the son of a mother--
- Yeah, actually, stop talking.\N- Okay, duly noted.
Let me just talk to him.
We tried that.
- He's my friend.\N- Yeah. And that's the problem.
Do you know for certain\Nwhat happens if he breaks the canon?
Do you wanna find out?\NI told you she was a liability.
You're wrong.
Jess, tell him he's wrong.
He's not.
Are you serious right now?
I told you.\NYou let him get away, I can't help you.
I'm not coming.
You're right.
What...?
What the hell?
Go home, Gwen.
We are supposed to be the good guys.
We are.
Jess, Ben. Come with me.
Hell, yeah.
And somebody catch Spot.
Yeah. Sorry.\NI gotta get her down for her nap.
Not you. I've had the right amount of you.
Hey, hon.
How was work?
I don't know.
Peter? Did you bring our baby\Nto another fight?
Did I bring our ba--? No. No, no.
'Cause you asked me not to.\NSo I didn't. I wouldn't.
Access denied. Access denied.
You think I'll be any good at this?
You're asking that now?
There's no playbook\Nfor raising someone like her...
or being someone like you.
You just gotta make\Nthe right adjustments at half-time.
- That's a sports metaphor, by the way.\N- I understand.
Sorry. You were just such a nerd\Nin high school. I figured--
But I have watched sports.
- Okay, champ.\N- Unbelievable.
Wanna go easy on the penguin?
Would you just...?
You gonna even look at me?
What? What is that?
I'm looking at you. Like you asked.
You look skinny.
Where have you been?
Just been, uh,\Nout murdering all my friends.
Oh, that's funny, yeah. Okay. Yeah. Okay.
-  Where are you going?\N- I don't know.
You're a good cop, Dad.
You put on that badge\Nbecause you know if you don't,
someone who shouldn't will.
But you have to understand,
this mask is my badge.
And I'm trying to be good too.
I was trying so hard
to wear this thing\Nthe way you would want...
and I didn't.
I didn't.
I can do all these things, but I can't\Nhelp the people I love the most.
And they can only know half of who I am.
So I'm completely on my own.
And now I don't even know\Nwhat the right thing is anymore.
I don't know what I'm supposed to do.\NBut I know...
I can't lose one more friend.
Gwen, I always taught you\Nto do it by the book.
And how did that work out?
- I took an oath.\N- Then arrest me, Dad.
- Get it over with.\N- I... I can't.
Why not?
Because I quit.
When?
About halfway through your big speech.
You're...
Wait a minute,\Nyou're not gonna be captain?
That means...
My job, being captain,
this whole thing doesn't matter anymore.
You're the best thing I've ever done.
- It was a good speech, huh?\N- No wonder you got an A in English.
B. I got a B-plus.
Missed a few classes.
I don't know what it is you gotta do...
but I think\Nthat this thing is supposed to help.
The guy who left it was\Na real piece of work.
I'll be right back.
Promise.
Parenting stuff is...
a big-ass mystery.
You're a mistake!
If you hadn't been bit,\Nyour Peter Parker would have lived.
And none of this would've happened.
Miles, the hardest thing about this job
is you can't always save everybody.
I'll make you pay\Nfor everything you took away from me.
You have a choice\Nbetween saving one person
and saving an entire world.
I can do both. Spider-Man always--
Not always.
Whatever you're gonna do out there,\Ndon't get lost.
-  Bad things are gonna happen.\N-  I didn't know how to tell you.
You were never supposed\Nto be Spider-Man.
Keep going.
Did you check your locations?
- Yes, Dad.\N- No sign of him.
LYLA, would you send everyone out?\NAnywhere. Anywhere he might be.
Congrats, captain.
"Captain"? You can't call me that\Nuntil I'm sworn in.
We're all proud of you. See you, jefe.
Perfect pose.
Possible disturbance in the alley.\NBetter go check it out.
Now I'm here in the alley.\NThere's something unusual happening.
Looking at the walls. Those are normal.
But there's something in front of me.
I made it.
I'm home.
Is now a bad time?
- Am I too late?\N- What'd you do to your hair?
Are you guys okay? Tell me you're okay.
I'm okay.
You were right.\NYou were right about everything.
Of course I'm right. I'm always right.
- What am I right about?\N- I saw all these amazing places
and met all these amazing people, but...
But they didn't want me.
I kept thinking about what you said.
And I let them have it, Mom.
I beat them all.
I know how strong I am now.
I'm strong because of you.
And Dad.
And us.
Mom.
There's something coming for us.
Something...
Something terrible.
Miles, you're talking crazy.\NWhat's going on?
His name is Spot. He's my nemesis.
And I'm gonna stop him.
I know you know I've been lying to you.
It's because I thought if you knew...
you wouldn't love me the same.
And then I went out there and...
And now...
I'm not afraid of anything.
What do you wanna tell me?
Promise nothing's gonna change.
- Papá, I will always love you.\N- You gotta promise.
Always. I don't care what you say.
Do ¿me entiendes?
Mom.
I'm...
I'm Spider-Man.
Who's Spider-Man?
The superhero? He got bit by a spider?
Gave him spider powers?
He's me?
Is this where you dress up\Nlike your favourite character for...?
What's it called? Comics-Con?
I don't know what that is.
You really had me going there. Spider-Man.
Why don't you have eight arms?
- Um...\N- Do you push silk out of your culito?
- I had a nightmare about that, but no.\N- Are you sure you woke up?
Mom, stop playing around. This is serious.
Dad worked with Spider-Man.
He didn't realise Spider-Man was me\Nat the time, but...
- I wish Dad was here to explain.\N- Miles, please.
I got you to take care of,\NI got me to take care of, so help me out.
Mom, hold on, hold on. I need to talk--
Oh, no.
He's in the wrong universe.
The spider that gave you\Nyour powers wasn't from your dimension.
- Forty-two.\N-  Its home dimension.
Dimensional signature identified.
That machine...
didn't send me home.
Uncle Aaron?
Hey.
You okay?
I missed you so much.
Okay. All right, then.
- Whoa, you took your braids out?\N- Uh...
- On purpose?\N- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm still getting used to it?
They gave me more hours at the hospital,\Nso next month I swear I'll pay you back.
Stop. Come on. We family.
Thanks.
-  Hey, honey, how you doing?\N- Hey. How'd it go with Miles?
- You know how you grounded him?\N- Mm-hm.
- I ungrounded him.\N- You what?
A little. I mean, how much trouble\Ncould he get into, right?
-  A lot of trouble!\N-  I don't wanna think about it.
Oh, Miles, I have to work\Nan overnight tonight.
- Here's the grocery list.\N- I'll make sure he gets these done.
All right, we gotta roll.
Security switches out at 6.\NThat's the window, right?
Right. Yeah.
I'm following you in what you are saying.
You all right?
I have a cold.
Come on, man.
Hey, you sure you got the plan?
Yeah, but maybe we should\Ngo over it one more time,
just to make sure there's no...
problems.
There's no Spider-Man here.
I'm sorry, baby,\Nbut you did unilaterally unground him.
Jeff...
I just worry about him getting\Nmixed up with the wrong people, okay?
This is probably that girl.
What is he even thinking, being with her?
I have some ideas.
- Baby, you're really not helping.\N- You saw the way he lit up around her.
I just hope she doesn't get him hurt.
I mean, am I responsible for this?
- No, no.\N- Maybe it's all my fault.
Come on, papá, you're a great dad.\NThis is hard.
This is hard.
It's like we got a whole new kid\Nwho just wants to grow up so fast.
And maybe we gotta grow up too.
A little bit.
Maybe we just gotta let him\Nspread his wings, man.
"Man"?
It's not your fault.
It's mine.
Oh, come on.\NWhat the heck are you doing here?
Oh, uh, his window was open so I came in.
Because that's normal to do.
I wanna talk to your parents.
Right. My, uh, dad's kind of hard\Nto get on the horn.
Oh, really? What does he do? Deal drugs?
He's a cop.
Statement withdrawn.
I'm gonna call the station.
I don't think he's there.\NOr anywhere around here.
- That's his jacket, emo. Where's Miles?\N- I don't know.
You don't know?\NWhat do you mean, you don't know?
Yeah, um, I'll leave.
Where do you think you're going,\Nyoung lady?
I'm going to find him.
I don't know where, exactly.
But I know where to start.
One thing I learned from Miles:
It's all possible.
He loves you more\Nthan you could ever imagine.
I've seen it.
If you do find him...
tell him five months.
And tell him we love him.
You got it.
Uncle Aaron?
Wait, wait.
Listen to me. Okay, look.
You don't understand. I'm not from here.
Listen, okay?\NThis machine sent me here by mistake.
Wait, wait, wait. Please. Please.
Uncle Aaron, wait, wait, wait.\NUncle Aaron!
Please. Uncle Aaron?
Just hear me out.
I was bit by a spider that gave me powers.
It wasn't supposed to bite me.\NIt was supposed to bite someone else.
Someone from here.
I don't belong here. I need to go home.
Okay?
I have an Uncle Aaron too. I had one.
- He was a bad guy called the Prowler.
He looked out for me.
He did a lot of bad things, but...
I knew he wanted to be good.
He just didn't know he had a choice,\Nbut you do.
You can be a good guy.
"A good guy"?
Please. Trust me.\NI know you don't wanna be the Prowler.
I'm not.
Mayor Manfredi\Nhas extended New York's mandatory curfew
as the so-called Sinister Six cartels\Nbattle for control on the streets.
Is nobody gonna try and stop them?
Your dad is still alive?
What?
Your father.
You said he's still alive.
Yeah.
Who are you?
I'm Miles Morales.
But you...
You can call me the Prowler.
If I don't get home...
our dad is gonna die.
Your dad.
Please.
You have to let me go.
Why would I do that?
Don't tell Mom.
I never found the right band to join.
So I started my own.
With a few old friends.
You want in?